Arch Oboler Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Film, circa 1925-1985, 31 linear feet (74 boxes)
  - The Bubble, 1963-1976
    - Production, 1952-1972
      - Follow-up, 1966 August (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Foreign reviews, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - "Freebies," 1966 May-June (Box 42, Folder 14)
        Product placement, etc.
      - Friedman, Lewis, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - Gibraltar Bank sets, 1966 July-1967 February (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - Gibraltar Progress article, 1966 December (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Gillman Film Corporation, 1968 February (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Glenn, Glen, undated (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - Globe Industries, 1965 April-1966 June (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - Gross receipts, undated (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - "H," 1966 August, October (Box 42, Folder 22)
      - Insurance, 1965 March, 1966 June-July (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - Insurance forms, undated (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - Los Angeles publicity, 1967 January-March (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - Legal documents, Schaeffer, 1952 November, 1966 September-1969 August (Box 42, Folder 26-27)
      - Memoranda, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 28)
      - Midwestern Magic-Vuers inventory, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 29)
      - Models, 1966 May-June (Box 42, Folder 30)
      - Music, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 31)
      - Newspaper ads, undated (Box 42, Folder 32)
      - Norton, Sam, 1963 June, 1964 May, 1965 February-March, 1966 January, June (Box 42, Folder 33)
      - Oboler's personal notes, circa 1966 July (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Oboler's personal production notes, 1966 July (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Opticals, 1966 October (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Photo stills, undated (Box 43, Folder 4-11)
      - Photos on set, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Plagiarism, 1967 January (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Polaroid, 1966 July (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Post production lists, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - Print cuts, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Production, casting, and payroll materials, 1966 (Box OS 2, Folder 2)
      - Props, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - Publicity
        - circa 1966 (Box 43, Folder 18)
        - Thomas and Maskel, 1966 November-1967 January (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - Radio and television spots, undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - Release forms, undated (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - Release print, 1967 January (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - Rental notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
      - Requests for funds, 1966 June-1967 February (Box 43, Folder 24)
      - "S," 1966 July (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Sales letter, 1968 February (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Script girl's notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Script pictures, circa 1966 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Script revisions, circa 1966 May (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Scripts submitted, circa 1963-1965 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - SEC, circa 1965 October (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Sets, 1966 June-July (Box 44, Folder 8-9)
      - Sherman correspondence, 1967 June-July (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Shooting notes, 1966 July-August (Box 44, Folder 11-12)
      - Shooting schedule, 1966 June-August (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Song
        - 1966 August (Box 44, Folder 14)
        - 1966 October, 1967 February (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Sound (Mike Dutton), circa 1966 September (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Sound effects, circa 1966 September-October (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Special effects, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Stereo realists, 1968-1972 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Stills, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Studio call sheets, 1966 July (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Studio daily production report, 1966 July-August (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Studios, 1966 May (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Three-dimensional process, circa 1962-1965 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Tickets, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Tower Auditing letters, 1966 April-1967June (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Tower correspondence, 1965 December-1967 June (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Trailer, 1966 December-1967 January (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Tru-D test, 1966 July (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - "V," 1966 August, 1967 January (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - Viewer comments, 1967 March-April (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Wardrobe notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Wild lines, circa 1966 July (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Sales and financing, 1962-1974
      - Australian distribution, 1970 September-1971 November (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Canadian distribution, circa 1968 October (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Distribution figures, circa 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Distribution follow-up file, 1966 May-1967 August (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Distribution follow-up file, 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Distribution statements, 1966-1969 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Finals given to Capitol, circa 1967 August (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Investors, 1963-1972 (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
      - Grosses, 1966-1970 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Los Angeles Times article, circa 1967 July (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963-1969 October (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - National general, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Ortega Distribution, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Possible investors, 1962 November-1965 May (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Press kit, circa 1966 (Box 46, Folder 14-15)
      - Sales breakdown and stock information, circa 1968 June-August, 1973 December (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Schedule of playdates, 1973 January-1974 August (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission first drafts, circa 1965 (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission samples, circa 1963 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Selected Pictures Corp. correspondence, 1962 June-1966 December (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Selected Pictures Corp. correspondence, 1967 January-1968 October (Box 47, Folder 7-8)
      - Selected Pictures Corp. correspondence notes, circa 1962 June-1966 December (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Tower and promissory notes, 1966 August, 1966 September, 1966 December (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Scripts, 1961-1966 and undated
      - Annotated script, undated (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
      - "Before Mimeo"
        - Draft, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
        - First corrected draft, 1961 October (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - First draft, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
        - First draft, 78 pages, 1962 February 28 (Box 48, Folder 7-8)
        - Motion picture script, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
        - Rough draft, undated (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
        - Second revision, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Synopsis, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Bernier 3-D effect ideas, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Final corrections, undated (Box 49, Folder 6-8)
      - "Final final" corrections, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Final revision
        - Scripts, circa 1966, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 49-50, Box 49, Box 50)
        - Yellow binder #3, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Yellow binder #4, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Yellow binder #18, undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
        - Yellow binder #59, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
        - Yellow binder #65, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
        - Yellow binder #66, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - First revision "After Mimeo," undated (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
      - First version, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Jerry Kay script book, circa 1966 July (Box 51, Folder 4-6)
      - Miscellaneous pages, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Post-production script, 1966 August, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 51-52, Box 51, Box 52)
      - Red binder, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Revisions for yellow script, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Script assistant's breakdown, undated (Box 52, Folder 4-5)
      - Second revision "After Mimeo," undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Script synopsis, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Script timing, revised, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Second version of Bubble, undated, (1 folder) (Box 52-53, Box 52, Box 53)
      - Sound effects, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - 3-D effect suggestions, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - 3-D test script, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - 3-D test and final mimeo draft, 1962 June 12 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
      - Visual effects script, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Theater openings, 1966-1968 and undated
      - Baton Rouge, Robert E. Lee Theater, 1967 June (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Canada, 1968 October-November (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Chicago, Woods Theater, 1966 December (Box 54, Folder 3-7)
      - Chicago, Woods Theater, miscellaneous, 1966 December (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Cleveland, Hippodrome, 1967 April (Box 54, Folder 9-10)
      - Denver, International 70 Theater, circa 1967 May (Box 54, Folder 11-12)
      - Detroit, Adams Theatre, 1967 February (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Detroit, Adams Theatre, miscellaneous, 1967 January-February (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Exhibitor billings, circa 1967 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Florida, Palms Theater, 1967 July (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Hawaii, 1967 March-April (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Imperial Beach, California, Palm Theatre, 1968 December (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Ivar advertisements, undated (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Ivar photographs, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Los Angeles, invitational premiere, circa 1967 March-July (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
      - Los Angeles, Ivar Theatre
        - Employees, 1967 March (Box 55, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous, 1967 March (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
        - Receipts, 1967 March (Box 56, Folder 3)
        - Variety pages, 1967 March (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Las Vegas, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Milwaukee, Palace Theatre, 1967 May (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Movie poster and draft advertising materials, undated (Box OS 1, Folder 2)
      - Movie poster and draft advertising materials, 1971, undated (Box OS 2, Folder 3)
      - New Orleans, Orpheum Theatre, circa 1967 May (Box 56, Folder 7-9)
      - New Orleans review, undated (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - "Opening Day Story," undated (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Palm Theater bumper stickers, undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - San Diego, Palms Theatre, undated (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - San Francisco, St. Francis Theater, 1967 April (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Teenage Fair, Hollywood Paladium, 1967 March (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Toronto, Downtown Theatre, 1968 November (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Woods photograph and negative, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Unions, 1966-1968
      - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), circa 1966-1967 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Cast, 1966 July (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Code certificate, 1966 November.-December. (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Contracts, circa 1966 - 1967 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Directors, 1966 April-May (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - Screen Actors Guild/Screen Extras Guild, 1966-1968 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Unions, 1966 April-1967 May (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Bwana Devil, 1925-1977 (bulk 1950s)
    Alternate title: The Lions of Gulu. Released: 1952 (Gulu Pictures), 1953 (United Artists). Production company: Gulu Pictures Co. Distribution company: Gulu Pictures Co., United Artists Corp. Director: Arch Oboler; assistant director: Richard Dixon. Producer: Arch Oboler; associate producer: Sid Pink; co-producer: William Shapiro. Writer: Arch Oboler. Cast includes: Robert Stack (Robert Hayward); Barbara Britton (Alice Hayward); Nigel Bruce (Doc Maclean). Photography: Joseph Biroc. Technical advisor: Louis Leakey. Special effects: Natural Vision three-dimensional process, possibly developed by Milton Gunzburg and licensed to Oboler by George J. Schaefer. Plot: When British railway workers in Kenya are repeatedly attacked by two man-eating lions, engineer Robert Hayward resolves to kill the animals. Following tragically unsuccessful attempts by skilled Masai tribesmen as well as renowned hunters sent in from London to kill the beasts, Hayward manages to shoot both of the lions.
    Notes: The film included footage taken by Oboler in Africa,1948-1950; other footage was shot in California and possibly Mexico. It was the first feature film to use the 3-D process. Bwana Devil was based on the true story of two man-eating lions that reportedly killed well over one hundred British East Africa railway workers in Kenya in the late 1890s. Following's the movie's release, a number of lawsuits were filed against Oboler by Edward Alperson, Milton Bren and his company Brenco Pictures, United Artists, and others.
    Unlike the materials documenting some of Oboler's other films, the Bwana Devil grouping contains few documents relating to performers and production. It does, however, include a large quantity of photographs, clippings, and promotional materials. The records also document various lawsuits filed after the movie's release and an Internal Revenue Service audit regarding taxes paid on the film's substantial earnings.
    - Contracts, 1952-1955
      - Arch Oboler Productions: application and license contract, circa 1952 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Bwana letter contracts employees, 1952 April-1954 August (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Research, 1952 April-December (Box 58, Folder 3)
        Includes Louis Leakey correspondence.
      - Bwana, 1952 May-November (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous contracts, Gulu, 1952 July-1955 May (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Print correspondence, Pathe and Consolidated, 1952 September-1955 February (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - Production contracts, 1952 May-September (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Distribution, 1952-1955
      - 1952 October-1953 April (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Distribution information, 1952 July-1953 February (Box 58, Folder 9)
      - George Schaefer, 1952 March-1955 November (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Sid Pink, 1952 January-1953 January (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Holly. & LA Paramount distribution contracts, 1952 July-1954 January (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Financial, 1951-1956
      - Bills, 1952 June-1953 September (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - Photostats of bills, 1952 May-1953 January (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
      - Bills paid personally by Oboler, 1951 September-1956 May (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Bills paid, 1952 June-1953 November (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Investors, 1952 May-1954 September (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Lou Berke correspondence, 1952 December-1956 April (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Gulu investor contracts, 1952 May-1954 September (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Milton Gunzburg, 1951-1954
      - 3685, Arch Oboler, regarding Milton Gunzburg, 1952 January-1954 January (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Gunzburg, 1951 October-1954 January (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1950-1960
      - Extra information Gov., 1952-1959 (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
      - Government information, 1953 September (Box 60, Folder 5-6)
      - Miscellaneous documents, 1950 July-1960 December (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - New information, Gov., 1951 October-1958 August (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
      - Taxes, government settlement regarding 1953 and 1954, 1954 January-1960 May (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Legal and lawsuits, Edward Alperson-Brenco Pictures, 1952-1957
      - Brenco v. Gulu Pictures, 1952-1953
        - 1760 B-2, folder file, 1952 December-1953 December (Box 61, Folder 5)
        - 1760-F, Sidney Pink deposition and exhibits, 1952 September-1953 September (Box 61, Folder 6)
        - 1760-J, Seymour M. Peyser deposition and exhibits, 1953 January-August (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
      - 1844-I, Arch Oboler v. Brenco, Jerry Kay deposition, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Alperson complaint, 1953 February-1956 March (Box 62, Folder 5-7)
      - Alperson trial, miscellaneous, 1952 December-1957 January (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Alperson trial, contracts, 1952 January-1957 January (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Sid Pink, 1952 January-1956 October (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Arch Oboler v. Brenco, 1955-1956
        - Appeal from the Superior Court, Los Angeles County, 1956 May (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - Appeal from the Superior Court, Los Angeles County, 1956 August (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
        - Deposition of Arch Oboler, 1956 February (Box 63, Folder 7-8)
        - Deposition of Arch Oboler, 1956 January-February (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
        - Deposition of Edward L. Alperson, 1955 September (Box 64, Folder 4)
        - Depositions of Graham L. Sterling, Jr., Lauren M. Wright, Pierce Works, and William B. Carman, 1956 April (Box 64, Folder 5)
        - Ledger, circa 1955 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
    - Legal and lawsuits, miscellaneous, 1925-1955
      - Sid Pink, Kamins, Pergament, 1952 June-1954 April (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Regarding Man-Eaters of Tsavo (Travis and John Henry Patterson), 1925, 1952 January-1955 June (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Cummins, 1952 August-1954 July (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Legal and lawsuits, United Artists, 1952-1958
      - Bills and miscellaneous bookkeeping, United Artists settlement, 1952 June-1956 May (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Bwana United Artists-Oboler dispute, 1952 August-1958 April (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1948-1953 and undated
      - Film opening photographs by Irving L. Antler, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - BD 1-BD 30, circa 1948-1950, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - BD 31-BD 60, 1948-1950, circa 1952 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - BD 61-BD 90, 1948-1950, circa 1952 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - BD 91-BD 120, 1948-1950, circa 1952 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - BD 121-BD 158, 1948-1950, circa 1952 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - "Bwana Pictures Advertising," 1952 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Premiere photographs from Arthur P. Jacobs, 1952 November 27 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous photographs, 1948-1950, circa 1952 (Box 68, Folder 3-6)
      - Personal appearances, circa 1952 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Photos from Africa filming, circa 1948-1950 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Belgium, 1953 April (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Mexico, undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Singapore, undated (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Production, filming, 1952-1956
      - Cutting notes, 1952 August-1954 November (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Employees, 1952 April-1953 April (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Equipment, 1952 August-1953 January (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Film lab, 1952 March-1953 April (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Music, 1952-1956 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Props, 1952 April-November (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Titles, 1952 March-1953 April (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Promotion, publicity, advertising,1925-1977 (bulk 1952-1954)
      - Openings: Cuba, India, London, Paris, Philippines, and Sweden photographs and articles, 1953 February-July (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Advertising, 1948 October, 1952 June-1954 September (Box 69, Folder 9-10)
      - Advertising, 1925, 1952 September-1953 March (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Advertising materials, 1952 December (Box OS 1, Folder 3)
      - Advertising materials, 1953 March (Box OS 2, Folder 4)
      - Denmark, 1953 May-1954 September (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Draft advertising materials, 1952 September (Box OS 1, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952 November-1953 October (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Europe, 1953 April-1954 January (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1953 March-April (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Opening, Los Angeles, 1953 March-1954 January (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Opening, Philadelphia, 1952 December (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Opening, San Francisco, 1952 November-December (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Personal appearances, 1952 December-1953 May (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Personal appearances, 1952 November-1954 August (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Premiere, television broadcast, 1952 November (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - Publicity, 1925, 1952 April-1954 November (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Second week, 1952 December, 1953 February (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Keyed proofs, undated (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous promotional and advertising materials, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - "The Nostalgic Saga of Bwana 3-D, Los Angeles Magazine, 1977 March 16 (Box 70, Folder 15)
      - Press and exploitation book, 1952, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 70-71, Box 70, Box 71)
      - Press folder, 1952 November (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - World premiere, Paramount Theatres, program, 1952 November 26 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Scripts, 1952 and undated
      - Call sheet, tentative shooting schedule, and script, 1952 June-July (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Lions of Gulu
        - undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
        - By Arch Oboler, undated (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
        - Kitchen Bwana, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
        - Movie, 1952 June-July (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Movie, ranch file, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
        - Incomplete, undated (Box 72, Folder 6-7)
      - Bwana script, 1952 June-September (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Domo Arigato, circa 1965-1976 and undated
    Alternate titles: Honeymoon; Thank You Very Much. Released: 1972. Production company: [Sherpix?]. Director: Arch Oboler; director's assistant: Jerry Kay; assistant director: Gary Sher. Producer: Arch Oboler; executive producer, Louis K. Sher. Writer: Arch Oboler. Cast includes: Bonnie Sher (Tara); Jason Ledger (Doug). Photographer: Donald Peterman. Special effects: "Space-Vision" three-dimensional process developed by Robert Bernier, who served as technical specialist on the film. Plot: Depicts the relationship between an American serviceman on leave from the war in Vietnam and the American girl he meets in Japan.
    Notes: Filmed in Japan, 1972. Financing was provided by Louis K. Sher. Lead actress Bonnie Sher was Lou Sher's daughter, and several additional family members also worked on the film. Domo Arigato was Oboler's last completed film.
    The materials are arranged as follows: Cast and crew; Included in this group of material is much information on financing production, and filming of the movie. Lou Sher's correspondence with Jerry Kay and Arch Oboler often concerns accounting and budgeting matters and requests for financial support. Kay prepared numerous financial spreadsheets and kept copious notes on budgets, salaries, bank depostits, and financial charges, all of which are retained in the Domo Arigato materials. Documents on the personnel involved with the film and on production and filming reveal the challenges of moviemaking in Japan. Camera reports, soundtrack notes, and various versions of scripts provide detailed information on the technical aspects of producing a motion picture.
    - Cast and crew, 1972
      - Contracts, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Crew contracts, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Crew, Honeymoon, 1972 July-December (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Contracts, 1965-1973
      - Legal and contractual documents with Sherpix, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Lou Sher, 1965-1966, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Motion pictures, agreements, 1972 June-July (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Sher contracts, 1972-1973 (Box 73, Folder 7-9)
    - Distribution, promotion, publicity, 1971-1976
      - Miscellaneous go thru, 1971-1973 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Follow-up, 1972 February-1976 September (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Financial, 1972-1974
      - Accounting sheets, Sherpix, 1972-1973 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Workbook, 1972-1973 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Petty cash, Arch Oboler and Jerry Kay, 1972 July-August (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Bills to be paid, 1972-1973 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - J.K. Sherpix accounting, 1972-1974 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Robert Sher, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Sherpix correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Third set of carbons sent to Robert Sher, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Worksheets, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972-1985
      - Correspondence, 1972 July-1985 March (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Jerry Kay notebook, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 6-9)
        Relates to all aspects of the film.